<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jacob Colvin</title><link>https://jacobcolvin.com/</link><description>Recent content on Jacob Colvin</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jacobcolvin.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Linkerd Multi-cluster Without a Public IP</title><link>https://jacobcolvin.com/posts/2023/04/linkerd-multi-cluster-without-a-public-ip/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jacobcolvin.com/posts/2023/04/linkerd-multi-cluster-without-a-public-ip/</guid><description>Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve set up Linkerd in my homelab. One of the features I was really interested in was Multi-cluster communication. This allows you to mirror services between clusters. Meaning, apps in one cluster can communicate with services in another cluster, as if they were in the same cluster.
Once you have Linkerd set up, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty easy to set up multi-cluster under ideal conditions. However, many problems arise if one of the clusters does not have the ability to create services of type LoadBalancer (with a Public, or otherwise routable IP address).</description></item><item><title>Building a Twin-ITX Cluster</title><link>https://jacobcolvin.com/posts/2023/04/building-a-twin-itx-cluster/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jacobcolvin.com/posts/2023/04/building-a-twin-itx-cluster/</guid><description>I am building a cluster that includes a Turing Pi (a mini-ITX cluster board), alongside a normal mini-ITX system. I wanted to put both of these in a single chassis to save space, which is possible with a &amp;ldquo;dual mini-itx&amp;rdquo;, or &amp;ldquo;twin-itx&amp;rdquo; chassis. This article covers most of the chassis I discovered.
As of writing, I have made a purchase (I went with the MyElectronics chassis) and am waiting for it to arrive.</description></item><item><title>Backups for K8s and Beyond</title><link>https://jacobcolvin.com/posts/2023/01/backups-for-k8s-and-beyond/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jacobcolvin.com/posts/2023/01/backups-for-k8s-and-beyond/</guid><description>Intro Recently I have been moving my homelab to Kubernetes. This has presented the need for a backup solution for any persistent data I might have there. For quite some time, I have been using Duplicati for my backups, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t been completely content with its performance, and have heard many horror stories of restores not working properly. So, I wanted to take this opportunity to find a backup solution that worked well for my personal computers (I have Windows, Linux, and Darwin hosts), my storage servers (UnRaid and FreeNAS), as well as Kubernetes.</description></item><item><title>About Me</title><link>https://jacobcolvin.com/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jacobcolvin.com/about/</guid><description>I love open source. I make most of the stuff I do in my free time public on GitHub. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot more detail about my current goals and projects on my profile.
I have a homelab and am slowly moving to an entirely IaC, all K8s setup with HCloud and several NUCs. I use both unraid and freenas for 100TB+ persistent storage.
I enjoy movies/tv and rate almost everything I watch on IMDB &amp;amp; MAL.</description></item><item><title>CV</title><link>https://jacobcolvin.com/cv/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jacobcolvin.com/cv/</guid><description>Source code • Download / View in Browser
Previous Next &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Page: /</description></item><item><title>How to use Grafana and Prometheus to Rickroll your friends (or enemies)</title><link>https://jacobcolvin.com/posts/2021/07/how-to-use-grafana-and-prometheus-to-rickroll-your-friends-or-enemies/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jacobcolvin.com/posts/2021/07/how-to-use-grafana-and-prometheus-to-rickroll-your-friends-or-enemies/</guid><description>Source code: https://github.com/MacroPower/prometheus_video_renderer
Read the blog post: https://grafana.com/blog/2021/07/30/how-to-use-grafana-and-prometheus-to-rickroll-your-friends-or-enemies/</description></item><item><title>HTB Challenge - Reversing - Baby RE</title><link>https://jacobcolvin.com/posts/2020/10/htb-challenge-reversing-baby-re/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jacobcolvin.com/posts/2020/10/htb-challenge-reversing-baby-re/</guid><description>We can start off by running ltrace, which runs a command and intercepts dynamic library &amp;amp; sys calls.
ltrace -i -C ./baby We&amp;rsquo;re prompted and can start off by inserting random value, e.g. asd.
A call to strcmp is intercepted by ltrace.
strcmp(&amp;#34;asd\n&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;ab[REDACTED]13\n&amp;#34;) Let&amp;rsquo;s start by trying to pass ab[REDACTED]13.
In this case it was just that simple, and we receive the flag.
HTB{B[REDACTED]Z} There were probably a lot of additional ways this one could have been solved, and I think I got lucky by starting in this direction.</description></item></channel></rss>